## ADHITHYAKRISHNA SRINIVASAN

adhithya.developer@gmail.com

Website | Linked-in

I am a software engineer with 3.5 years of work experience in e-commerce domain. I have 1.5 years of experience as a frontend developer on technologies such as jQuery, handlebars, Html5 and CSS. I was promoted as a backend developer for developing microservices using Spring and have a work experience of 1.7 years as a backend developer.

I have a good knowledge in creating scalable microservices using Spring and integrating the restful Api endpoints to the front-end using frontend frameworks. I also have an excellent knowledge in creating pixel perfect responsive websites using Html5 and CSS3.

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Backend developer, Skava Systems - (DEC 2017 - JUN 2019)

- Developed microservices for e-commerce website using Spring framework to handle user authentication, validation and storage of user information in MySQL database.
- Developed MapReduce project using Apache Hadoop to fetch profile data of users from MySQL database and store them to the Apache Solr server for faster user search.
- Generated site usage report from Amazon Cloud Watch logs using Apache Hadoop which was used to analyze and improve the site's efficiency and decrease page load latency.

### Frontend developer, Skava Systems - (JUN 2016 - NOV 2017)

- Developed responsive websites using HTML5, CSS3, handlebars and jQuery that supported multitude of devices ranging from mobile to in-store kiosks.
- Developed customizable plug-ins from scratch using jQuery to replace the feature-bloated third-party plug-ins.
- Integrated Google analytics to the website to analyze the traffic flow and site usage metrics in real-time.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Masters in Computer science, University at Buffalo – (AUG 2019 – JAN 2021)

Pursuing my first semester. **Courses taken** – Information retrieval, Introduction to machine learning, Algorithms for modern computing systems and Object-oriented design and analysis.

Bachelors in Computer Science, Kumaraguru college of Technology – (AUG 2012 – AUG 2016)

**Courses taken** – Visual programming, Database management, Data structures, Object oriented programming, Computer architecture, Java programming, Compiler design.

#### SKILLS

• Java • CSS 3 • MySql

JavaScript, jQuery
 Html 5
 Maven
 Express JS
 Mongo dB

# **PROJECTS**

Academic projects – <u>Twitter rhetoric analysis</u> - <u>Evaluation of information retrieval models</u>

Non-Academic projects – <u>Sprite image mapper</u> - <u>Telegram to Gdrive</u>